### Rebecca Lama Moktan

Mobile: +9739684163

Email: rebeccalamamoktan798@gmail.com rebeccalamamoktan@gmail.com

### **Professional Summary**

3.9 years of experience as Business Development and Key Account Manager collaborating with Sales, Marketing, Business and Supply Teams. Hard-working, Dedicated, Positive attitude team player in a variety of products and services seeking a position allowing the utilization and enhancement of my skills and Willingness to learn, enthusiastic, involved in management and development of new business opportunities.

## **Professional Experience:**

- Excellent understanding of sales tactics and marketing strategies
- Proficient in computer programs and data entry
- Great customer service skills
- Experience with telesales inbound sales and personal sales
- Exceptional communication skills with customers as well as coworkers and employers
- Ability to multitask and remain organized
- Capable of operating a multi-line phone system or switchboard
- Proven stability and loyalty to a company

Telephone Sales Representative Feb 2016- Dec 2017 Hinduja Global Solutions Near RSS motors' Bommanahalli

- Answer calls from customers inquiring about products and services offered by clients
- Place sales calls to prospective customers or previous customers
- Attend meetings introducing and explaining products and services available to customers
- Answer customer inquiries, take messages, transfer calls etc.
- Worked as a substitute teacher for Christ Jyoti School for 6 months.
- Worked as an SDM in HDFC Standard Life.

# **Key Account Manager at Intelenet(Flipkart Process) May 2018 – Dec 2018**

- Developing trust relationships with a portfolio of major Sellers (Gold Tier) to ensure they satisfy the customer requirement by bringing the desired product(s).
- Acquiring a thorough understanding of key customer/seller needs and requirements.
- Ensure the correct products and services are delivered to customers in a timely manner that is by following the metrics of Flipkart in terms of processing the orders within the SLA.
- Serve as the link of communication between key Sellers and internal teams
- Resolve any issues and problems faced by Sellers and deal with complaints to maintain trust
- Play an integral part in generating new sales that will turn into long-lasting relationships.
- Prepare regular reports of progress and forecasts to internal and external stakeholders using key account metrics.
- Joint business planning, promotion, PLA and assortment planning.
- Negotiation and selling, preparing forecast/sales plans.

# Senior Business Development Manager Meesho Dec 2018 – April 2020

- Market Research to onboard new and top suppliers to meet category and company requirements.
- Cold calling, in-person meeting, pitching, consulting, negotiating and closing deals.
- Lead generation write emails and reach out to suppliers on daily-basis.
- Qualify leads as sales opportunities and pursue for closure.
- Developed sales collaterals, case studies and SOPs to onboard new suppliers who has less exposure of ecommerce.
- Expertise in expanding sales area-wise (Northeast, Bhagalpur, North Karnataka and Rural Part of TN) and Category wise based on demand.
- Present company to potential Brands and onboard them to our platform to meet end customer requirements.
- Meeting up the target within limited period of set by the company.

- Resolving and assisting in issues related to Catalogs and other issues to newly onboarded supplier, connecting them with relevant teams.
- Assist the supplier in receiving 70 orders in the initial phase.
- Brining new selection as per trend and requirement from category within best price along with competition insights.

### **Education:**

- B.A from G.P Women College, Manipur.
- HSE from TG Higher Secondary School.
- S.S.C from Christ Jyoti School, Manipur.

### **Skills and Attributes**

- Knowledge of Microsoft Word, Excel, Outlook and PowerPoint as well as various process unique applications and databases.
- Exceptional versatility with the ability to manage multiple tasks in a pressured environment.
- Excellent communication, interpersonal, organizational skills with proven abilities in training & development, customer relationship management and planning and leadership skills.
- Motivated to learn and keen to further personal development.

#### **Personal Details**

Name : Rebecca Lama Moktan Father's Name : Sushil Lama Moktan Mother's Name : Devina Lama Moktan

Gender : Female

Date of Birth : 16 Jan 1992

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Nepali, and Manipuri.

Hobbies : Preaching and Reading Books, Playing Guitar and singing

Marital Status : Single

I hereby declare that the information given above is complete and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Rebecca Lama Moktan

Place: Bangalore